<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorials on MLIR</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tutorials/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorials on MLIR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a Dialect</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tutorials/CreatingADialect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tutorials/CreatingADialect/</guid><description>CMake best practices TableGen Targets Library Targets CMake best practices Public dialects are typically separated into at least 3 directories:
mlir/include/mlir/Dialect/Foo (for public include files) mlir/lib/Dialect/Foo (for sources) mlir/lib/Dialect/Foo/IR (for operations) mlir/lib/Dialect/Foo/Transforms (for transforms) mlir/test/Dialect/Foo (for tests) Along with other public headers, the &amp;lsquo;include&amp;rsquo; directory contains a TableGen file in the ODS format , describing the operations in the dialect. This is used to generate operation declarations (FooOps.</description></item><item><title>Defining Dialect Attributes and Types</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tutorials/DefiningAttributesAndTypes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tutorials/DefiningAttributesAndTypes/</guid><description>This document is a quickstart to defining dialect specific extensions to the attribute and type system . The main part of the tutorial focuses on defining types, but the instructions are nearly identical for defining attributes.
See MLIR specification for more information about MLIR, the structure of the IR, operations, etc.
Types Types in MLIR (like attributes, locations, and many other things) are value-typed. This means that instances of Type should be passed around by-value, as opposed to by-pointer or by-reference.</description></item><item><title>Quickstart tutorial to adding MLIR graph rewrite</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tutorials/QuickstartRewrites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Tutorials/QuickstartRewrites/</guid><description>This document will present a quickstart to adding graph rewrites. We shall start by defining an operation, showing multiple ways to define the rewrite using patterns, as well as defining the rewrite using a graph walker (note: using patterns and the rewrite engine is preferred, showing the walker is for demonstration purposes).
See MLIR specification for more information about MLIR, the structure of the IR, operations, etc. See Table-driven Operation Definition and Declarative Rewrite Rule for the detailed explanation of all available mechanisms for defining operations and rewrites in a table-driven manner.</description></item></channel></rss>