<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Code Documentation on MLIR</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Code Documentation on MLIR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Background: declarative builders API</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/EDSC/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/EDSC/</guid><description>The main purpose of the declarative builders API is to provide an intuitive way of constructing MLIR programmatically. In the majority of cases, the IR we wish to construct exhibits structured control-flow. Declarative builders provide an API to make MLIR construction and manipulation very idiomatic, for the structured control-flow case, in C++.
ScopedContext mlir::edsc::ScopedContext provides an implicit thread-local context, supporting a simple declarative API with globally accessible builders. These declarative builders are available within the lifetime of a ScopedContext.</description></item><item><title>Conversion to the LLVM Dialect</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/ConversionToLLVMDialect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/ConversionToLLVMDialect/</guid><description>Conversion from the Standard to the LLVM Dialect can be performed by the specialized dialect conversion pass by running
mlir-opt -convert-std-to-llvm &amp;lt;filename.mlir&amp;gt; It performs type and operation conversions for a subset of operations from standard dialect (operations on scalars and vectors, control flow operations) as described in this document. We use the terminology defined by the LLVM IR Dialect description throughout this document.
Type Conversion Scalar Types Index Type Vector Types Memref Types Function Types Calling Convention Function Signature Conversion Result Packing Calling Convention for memref C-compatible wrapper emission Repeated Successor Removal Default Memref Model Memref Descriptor Index Linearization Type Conversion Scalar Types Scalar types are converted to their LLVM counterparts if they exist.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Dialect</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/CreatingADialect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/CreatingADialect/</guid><description>CMake best practices TableGen Targets Library Targets CMake best practices Public dialects are typically separated into at least 3 directories:
mlir/include/mlir/Dialect/Foo (for public include files) mlir/lib/Dialect/Foo (for sources) mlir/lib/Dialect/Foo/IR (for operations) mlir/lib/Dialect/Foo/Transforms (for transforms) mlir/test/Dialect/Foo (for tests) Along with other public headers, the &amp;lsquo;include&amp;rsquo; directory contains a TableGen file in the ODS format , describing the operations in the dialect. This is used to generate operation declarations (FooOps.</description></item><item><title>Dialect Conversion</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/DialectConversion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/DialectConversion/</guid><description>This document describes a framework in MLIR in which to perform operation conversions between, and within dialects. This framework allows for transforming illegal operations to those supported by a provided conversion target, via a set of pattern-based operation rewriting patterns.
Modes of Conversion Conversion Target Recursive Legality Rewrite Pattern Specification Restrictions Type Conversion Type Converter Conversion Patterns Region Signature Conversion To utilize the framework, a few things must be provided:</description></item><item><title>Introduction and Usage Guide to MLIR's Diagnostics Infrastructure</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Diagnostics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Diagnostics/</guid><description>Source Locations CallSite Location FileLineCol Location Fused Location Name Location Opaque Location Unknown Location Diagnostic Engine Constructing a Diagnostic Diagnostic Appending arguments Attaching notes InFlight Diagnostic Diagnostic Configuration Options Print Operation On Diagnostic Print StackTrace On Diagnostic Common Diagnostic Handlers Scoped Diagnostic Handler SourceMgr Diagnostic Handler SourceMgr Diagnostic Verifier Handler Parallel Diagnostic Handler This document presents an introduction to using and interfacing with MLIR&amp;rsquo;s diagnostics infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to MLIR Interfaces</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Interfaces/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Interfaces/</guid><description>MLIR is generic and very extensible; it allows for opaquely representing many different dialects that have their own operations, attributes, types, and so on. This allows for dialects to be very expressive in their semantics and for MLIR to capture many different levels of abstraction. The downside to this is that transformations and analyses must be extremely conservative about the operations that they encounter, and must special-case the different dialects that they support.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to MLIR Operation Traits</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Traits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Traits/</guid><description>Defining a Trait Parametric Traits Attaching a Trait Using a Trait Trait List Broadcastable Commutative Function-Like HasParent IsolatedFromAbove Single Block with Implicit Terminator Symbol SymbolTable Terminator MLIR allows for a truly open operation ecosystem, as any dialect may define operations that suit a specific level of abstraction. Traits are a mechanism in which to abstract implementation details and properties that are common across many different operations.</description></item><item><title>Linalg Dialect Rationale: The Case For Compiler-Friendly Custom Operations</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/RationaleLinalgDialect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/RationaleLinalgDialect/</guid><description>Introduction Positioning Inception Evolution Prior Art Lessons from ONNX Lessons from LIFT Lessons from XLA Lessons from Halide and TVM Lessons from Tensor Comprehensions Lessons from Polyhedral compilers Lessons from the Affine dialect Core Guiding Principles Transformations and Simplicity First Preservation of Information Composable and Declarative Transformations Suitability for Search and Machine Learning Extensibility and Future-Proofness Key Observations Algorithms + Data Structures = Programs The Dialect Need not be Closed Under Transformations Summary of Existing Alternatives a Picture Introduction Positioning This document describes the key design principles that led to the existing implementation of Linalg and aims at exposing the tradeoffs involved when building higher-level Intermediate Representations (IR) and Dialects to facilitate code generation.</description></item><item><title>MLIR Generic DAG Rewriter Infrastructure</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/GenericDAGRewriter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/GenericDAGRewriter/</guid><description>Introduction and Motivation The goal of a compiler IR is to represent code - at various levels of abstraction which pose different sets of tradeoffs in terms of representational capabilities and ease of transformation. However, the ability to represent code is not itself very useful - you also need to be able to implement those transformations.
There are many different sorts of compiler transformations, but this document focuses on a particularly important class of transformation that comes up repeatedly at scale, and is important for the immediate goals of MLIR: that of pattern matching on a set of operations and replacing with another set.</description></item><item><title>MLIR Passes</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Passes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Passes/</guid><description>This document describes the available MLIR passes and their contracts.
Affine control lowering (-lower-affine) Input invariant Output IR Invariants Conversion from Standard to LLVM IR dialect (-convert-std-to-llvm) Input invariant Output IR Data Copy DMA generation (-affine-data-copy-generate) Loop tiling (-affine-loop-tile) Loop unroll (-affine-loop-unroll) Loop unroll and jam (-affine-loop-unroll-jam) Loop fusion (-affine-loop-fusion) Memref bound checking (-memref-bound-check) Memref dataflow optimization (-memref-dataflow-opt) Memref dependence analysis (-memref-dependence-check) Pipeline data transfer (-affine-pipeline-data-transfer) Affine control lowering (-lower-affine) Convert operations related to affine control into a graph of blocks using operations from the standard dialect.</description></item><item><title>MLIR Quantization</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Quantization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Quantization/</guid><description>This document outlines the design of the MLIR quantization system. While the term &amp;ldquo;quantization&amp;rdquo; is highly overloaded, in this case, it refers to a fairly narrow scope of techniques in use to enable conversion of floating-point computations to corresponding and plausible variants expressed in integer math for inference, as has historically been supported by low-bit depth inference engines such as TFLite, various accelerator hardware, and many DSPs.
Much of this is inspired by the approach taken in this paper with many extensions and adaptations folded in.</description></item><item><title>MLIR Rationale</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Rationale/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Rationale/</guid><description>This document is intended to capture some of the alternatives considered and open debates in the design of MLIR, along with the rationale for certain decisions we made. This is not intended to be a &amp;ldquo;finely groomed&amp;rdquo; document - we prefer the ability to dump in interesting tidbits without worrying too much about their consistency or readability.
Abstract Introduction and Motivation Design Decisions Loads and stores Symbols and types Block Arguments vs PHI nodes Index type disallowed in vector/tensor/memref types Bit width of a non-primitive types and index is undefined Integer signedness semantics Splitting floating point vs integer operations Specifying sign in integer comparison operations Specifying comparison kind as attribute &amp;lsquo;select&amp;rsquo; operation to implement min/max Regions Quantized integer operations Dialect type extensions Tuple types Assembly forms Examples Non-affine control flow Non-affine loop bounds Reference 2D Convolution Design alternatives and extensions Polyhedral code representation alternatives: schedule lists vs schedules trees vs affine loop/if forms Affine Relations Regions Read/Write/May_Read/May_Write sets for External Functions Memref Extensions affine.</description></item><item><title>MLIR Specification</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/LangRef/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/LangRef/</guid><description>MLIR (Multi-Level IR) is a compiler intermediate representation with similarities to traditional three-address SSA representations (like LLVM IR or SIL ), but which introduces notions from polyhedral loop optimization as first-class concepts. This hybrid design is optimized to represent, analyze, and transform high level dataflow graphs as well as target-specific code generated for high performance data parallel systems. Beyond its representational capabilities, its single continuous design provides a framework to lower from dataflow graphs to high-performance target-specific code.</description></item><item><title>MLIR: Incremental Application to Graph Algorithms in ML Frameworks</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/MLIRForGraphAlgorithms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/MLIRForGraphAlgorithms/</guid><description>The existing documentation about MLIR focuses on long term vision, how its pieces fit together, and the benefits of modular and composable infrastructure in the vast and distant future. While this viewpoint appeals to some, it causes concern for others who are more concerned about the &amp;ldquo;here and now&amp;rdquo; - why does it make sense to make a &amp;ldquo;revolutionary&amp;rdquo; change when any individual problem can be fixed in place?
This document explains that adoption of MLIR to solve graph based problems isn&amp;rsquo;t a revolutionary change: it is an incremental series of steps which build on each other, each of which delivers local value.</description></item><item><title>MLIR: The case for a simplified polyhedral form</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/RationaleSimplifiedPolyhedralForm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/RationaleSimplifiedPolyhedralForm/</guid><description>MLIR embraces polyhedral compiler techniques for their many advantages representing and transforming dense numerical kernels, but it uses a form that differs significantly from other polyhedral frameworks.
Disclaimer / Warning
This document is a very early design proposal (which has since been accepted) that explored the tradeoffs of using this simplified form vs the traditional polyhedral schedule list form. At some point, this document could be dusted off and written as a proper academic paper, but until now, it is better to included it in this crafty form than not to.</description></item><item><title>Operation Canonicalization in MLIR</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Canonicalization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/Canonicalization/</guid><description>Canonicalization is an important part of compiler IR design: it makes it easier to implement reliable compiler transformations and to reason about what is better or worse in the code, and it forces interesting discussions about the goals of a particular level of IR. Dan Gohman wrote an article exploring these issues; it is worth reading if you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with these concepts.
Most compilers have canonicalization passes, and sometimes they have many different ones (e.</description></item><item><title>Quickstart tutorial to adding MLIR graph rewrite</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/QuickstartRewrites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/QuickstartRewrites/</guid><description>This document will present a quickstart to adding graph rewrites. We shall start by defining an operation, showing multiple ways to define the rewrite using patterns, as well as defining the rewrite using a graph walker (note: using patterns and the rewrite engine is preferred, showing the walker is for demonstration purposes).
See MLIR specification for more information about MLIR, the structure of the IR, operations, etc. See Table-driven Operation Definition and Declarative Rewrite Rule for the detailed explanation of all available mechanisms for defining operations and rewrites in a table-driven manner.</description></item><item><title>Quickstart tutorial to defining custom dialect attributes and types</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/DefiningAttributesAndTypes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/DefiningAttributesAndTypes/</guid><description>This document is a quickstart to defining dialect specific extensions to the attribute and type system . The main part of the tutorial focuses on defining types, but the instructions are nearly identical for defining attributes.
See MLIR specification for more information about MLIR, the structure of the IR, operations, etc.
Types Types in MLIR (like attributes, locations, and many other things) are value-typed. This means that instances of Type should be passed around by-value, as opposed to by-pointer or by-reference.</description></item><item><title>Shape inference</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/ShapeInference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/ShapeInference/</guid><description>Shape inference as discussed here is considered a specific instance of type inference for ShapedType . Type constraints are along (at least) three axis: 1) elemental type, 2) rank (including static or dynamic), 3) dimensions. While some operations have no compile time fixed shape (e.g., output shape is dictated by data) we could still have some knowledge of constraints/bounds in the system for that operation (e.g., the output of a tf.</description></item><item><title>Symbols and Symbol Tables</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/SymbolsAndSymbolTables/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/SymbolsAndSymbolTables/</guid><description>Symbol Defining a Symbol Symbol Table Referencing a Symbol Manipulating a Symbol Symbol Visibility With Regions , the multi-level aspect of MLIR is structural in the IR. A lot of infrastructure within the compiler is built around this nesting structure; including the processing of operations within the pass manager . One advantage of the MLIR design is that it is able to process operations in parallel, utilizing multiple threads.</description></item><item><title>Table-driven Declarative Rewrite Rule (DRR)</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/DeclarativeRewrites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/DeclarativeRewrites/</guid><description>In addition to subclassing the mlir::RewritePattern C++ class, MLIR also supports defining rewrite rules in a declarative manner. Similar to Op Definition Specification (ODS), this is achieved via TableGen , which is a language to maintain records of domain-specific information. The rewrite rules are specified concisely in a TableGen record, which will be expanded into an equivalent mlir::RewritePattern subclass at compiler build time.
This manual explains in detail all of the available mechanisms for defining rewrite rules in such a declarative manner.</description></item><item><title>Table-driven Operation Definition Specification (ODS)</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/OpDefinitions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/OpDefinitions/</guid><description>In addition to specializing the mlir::Op C++ template, MLIR also supports defining operations in a table-driven manner. This is achieved via TableGen , which is both a generic language and its tooling to maintain records of domain-specific information. Facts regarding an operation are specified concisely into a TableGen record, which will be expanded into an equivalent mlir::Op C++ template specialization at compiler build time.
This manual explains in detail all the available mechanisms for defining operations in such a table-driven manner.</description></item><item><title>Usage of 'Const' in MLIR, for core IR types</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/UsageOfConst/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/UsageOfConst/</guid><description>aka, where&amp;rsquo;d const go?
The MLIR data structures that represent the IR itself (Instruction, Block, etc) form a graph-based data structure, and the compiler analyses and passes frequently walk this graph (e.g. traversing from defs to users). The early design of MLIR adopted the const model of LLVM, which is familiar and well understood (even though the LLVM implementation is flawed in many ways).
The design team since decided to change to a different module, which eschews const entirely for the core IR types: you should never see a const method on Operation, should never see the type const Value, and you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t feel bad about this.</description></item><item><title>Writing a Pass</title><link>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/WritingAPass/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mlir.llvm.org/docs/WritingAPass/</guid><description>Operation Pass OperationPass : Op-Specific OperationPass : Op-Agnostic Analysis Management Querying Analyses Preserving Analyses Pass Failure Pass Manager OpPassManager Pass Registration Pass Pipeline Registration Textual Pass Pipeline Specification Instance Specific Pass Options Pass Statistics Pass Instrumentation Standard Instrumentations Crash and Failure Reproduction Passes represent the basic infrastructure for transformation and optimization. This document provides a quickstart to the pass infrastructure in MLIR and how to use it.</description></item></channel></rss>